qu.edu.qa 2016-06-08

# Privacy Policy and Legal Disclaimer

Last modified: November 09, 2013 10:35:16.

## Privacy Policy

### Information about the Website

The Qatar University website is managed by the Websites Unit in the External Relations Department's Communications and Marketing Section, with support from the Information Technology Services Department

### Scope

This Privacy Policy applies to all sites on the Qatar University web domain “qu.edu.qa”. Since the QU web community consists of several websites, other websites may adopt different privacy and security statements as their specific needs require. The QU website, as well as other sites across campus, contain links to various external websites. The University is not responsible for the privacy and security practices or the content of external websites linked to.

### Providing Visitors with Anonymous Access

You can access our website homepage and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. Your personal data are requested only if you want to access online services (e.g. QU email, myQU, or other registration services). We do not sell or provide any third party with any of the data you disclosed.   
Users surfing and reading information on the website can expect QU, just as any other website, to collect and store the following anonymous information about your visit:

  * The operating system and browser your computer uses.

  * Any search engine you were using before arriving to the website.

  * The date and time of your visit.

  * The URLs of the pages you visit on the website.

The Websites Unit only uses this anonymous data for statistical purposes, and will not provide it to any third party. We may keep more extensive information if we are concerned, for example, about security issues (attacks against the Website). If necessary, or following a request of the relevant public authority, we may then keep and give additional information to the relevant authority, as necessarywithin the legal framework of the law of Qatar.

### The Services and links of the Website

The QU Home Website does not enable visitors to communicate with other visitors, or to post information to be accessed by others.

### Automatic Collection of Information

We do not automatically log personal data, nor do we link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals.

### Data Collection and Purpose Specification

The Websites Unit will collect personal data that you may volunteer while using our survey services. We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organizations.

### Disclosure and Visitor Choice

We do not disclose your personal data to any other individual or organization.

### Privacy Support

If you have an enquiry or concern about the Websites Unit privacy policy, please contact us on: [webadmin@qu.edu.qa](mailto:webadmin@qu.edu.qa)

### Change of this policy

Qatar University reserves the right to change, adapt, and adjust this privacy policy without prior notification. By reading this document, users of the website acknowledge that the terms of this policy may change, that only the latest version will be applicable, and that this latest version will be available on the QU website.

## Legal Disclaimer

### IMPORTANT

The QU Website (the Website) is an information portal provided by Qatar University. QU welcomes you on this Website. Please read the present legal disclaimer. By continuing to view the pages of this Website, you do acknowledge that you did read and accept the present disclaimer. If you do not want to accept the legal disclaimer and/or the privacy policy, you should leave the Website. You also acknowledge and agree that you only are allowed to visit and use the Website by strictly following the rules described in this legal disclaimer.

If you do not respect the legal disclaimer and/or the privacy policy, Qatar University may block your access to the Website and take any future action as appropriate. Qatar University may change this legal disclaimer and/or Privacy Policy at any time, and these modifications will be effective immediately after they become available online. You agree to periodically read the present legal disclaimer and Privacy policy in order to be aware of any change in the wording of the present document. You agree to systematically be bound by the latest version of the present legal disclaimer and privacy policy.

All trademarks used in the design of the Website are the sole property of Qatar University.

### INFORMATION

The contents of the Qatar University Website are protected by law. Unless otherwise stated, you are not free to distribute any text or photos without prior permission from the University.

The information presented on the Qatar University Website comes from a variety of sources. It includes information about official Qatar University departments and colleges, as well as affiliated pages from various sources and individuals. Every effort is made to present current and accurate information, yet the Websites Unit does not author or edit all of the pages on this website and cannot assume responsibility for all information. The author of each web page is responsible for the content of that page and is expected to abide by QU policies. Feedback or issues submitted to the site will be sent to the respective author.

### INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY

Qatar University is the sole owner of all copyright and other intellectual property rights (Trademarks, patents, etc.) of every element of the Website. Every element of the Website is protected by copyright, unless expressively stated. No copy of any element of the website may be reproduced or distributed for any purpose without QU's express authorization.

### LINK TO OTHER WEBSITES

Hyperlinks to third-party websites may exist on the Website for information only. Qatar University is and will be not responsible for any content of these websites. The presence of any hyperlink does not constitute any endorsement of the content of the website, and does not mean that Qatar University made any audit, verification, or investigation of the content of these websites.

### APPLICABLE LAW

The Website is governed only by the laws of Qatar.
